### Joshua Smith

Email: <a href="mailto:smithjk@infosecworx.com">smithjk@infosecworx.com</a> | <a href="mailto:LinkedIn">LinkedIn</a>

Twitter: <a>@n0hats</a>

## - Summary -

As a seasoned Information Security professional with 15 years of comprehensive experience across all security domains, my specialization lies in proactively defending against evolving threats by staying abreast of the latest trends. I take pleasure in collaborating with and mentoring junior professionals, assisting them in identifying their strengths and weaknesses.

**Specialties**: Splunk, MITRE ATT&CK (Attack), NipperStudio, Burp Suite Pro, Metasploit Framework, PowerShell, IDA Pro, Ghidra, Nessus, Nmap, Python

## - Professional Experience -

# Devo Technology, Inc.

# Senior Detection Engineer

Sept 2020 - Jan 2024

- Led the development of a Flask-based Python application to streamline the detection creation process, automating the input of relevant information and outputting the necessary files for ingestion into Devo
- Managed exploit research involving the collection of logs and identification of signatures to generate alert content for the SIEM.
- Developed PowerShell scripts that executed atomic tests individually or collectively; enhancing the organization's capabilities
- Established an extensive array of detections for various CVEs, showcasing a proficiency in identifying and mitigating vulnerabilities through strategic and effective security measures

### **Syntasa Corporation**

# Senior Security Advisor

Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

- Managed overall security posture of multiple geographically dispersed locations through comprehensive risk assessments and targeted security measures
- Defined the processes necessary to ensure compliance with Agency regulations
- Provided daily briefings to senior leadership on the security posture of each site
- Developed remediation plans with sites when a potential vulnerability was identified

### Ingenium Consulting, LLC

## **Container Security Expert**

Sept 2019 - Dec 2019

- Deployed docker containers Enterprise wide
- Collaborated over multiple disciplines to ensure a security centric approach
- Led the requirements gathering and workflow identification for the Enterprise Docker solution
- Managed stakeholder meetings to ensure concerns were addressed

# Joshua Smith smithjk@infosecworx.com | LinkedIn

Page 2 of 2

# **Pathoras / Proaptiv Corporation**

### Senior Penetration Tester

Mar 2016 - Sept 2019

- Led multiple blue team penetration tests on AWS instances
- Conducted penetration tests on clients' VoIP systems, successfully identifying vulnerabilities and implementing robust security measures
- Mentored junior staff, offering training and career guidance to foster professional development

#### **Mantech International**

## Senior Cyber Defense Specialist

Aug 2011 - Sept 2019

- Managed Red Team offensive operations
- Collaborated with multiple USG components to perform offensive technical operations

## **BAE Systems, Inc**

## Lead Cyber Forensics Specialist

Jul 2009 - Aug 2011

Performed forensic analysis of various media using FTK and EnCase

## **Perot Systems Government Services**

## Information Systems Security Officer

Nov 2005 - Jul 2009

• Led the review process in ensuring each SSP was complete and in compliance

## - Education -

2008 George Mason University B.S.Information Technology